<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-29T21:11:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Guardian Journal</title><subtitle>This is my site
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What Next</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/29/What-Now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Next" /><published>2023-07-29T02:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T02:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/07/29/What-Now</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/07/29/What-Now.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/n-map-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>
I don't know who I am, or quite understand what I want this site to be. I know what I would like to say, but have no idea how to organize my thoughts to say it. I have a million thoughts and a million interconnected projects - and it is impossible to present it as any one thing. I came upon this concept called digital gardens, and saw so many sites organized the way my mind is organized, and now I know that is what I want to do. Over the next year or two I plan to destroy this site and transform it into a digital garden - a web of interconnected thoughts, projects and philosophies. My brain is exploding at the mere attempts to organize it into a linear construct that can be understood.
</p>
<p>
I hate programming and web development. These are things I do, but I hate it. I hate people, but I love them too. I build sites and program because if I don't know one else will. So I head bang my way through problems that take me days or weeks to solve, even posting this website was a nightmare. I spent 1 week trying to do what someone else can do in a day. So much of my time is spent trying to get things like github to work, trying to remember how to use jekyll when I've just spent the past several months in blender, or remembering how to use blender when I've spent the past several months working on my book.
</p>
<p>
Half of the time I spend trying to figure out why git push doesn't work today when it worked yesterday, and what's the most affordable next to nothing thing I can find that doesn't break my brain to host a website, that might as well be called a hobby. In the end I am overwhelmed. My plan now is to take a hiatus from the website, and refocus my energy on digital gardens.
</p>
<p>
I intend to build a digital garden, and various interconnected wikis. It will either be one site or multiple sites with nodes to click through. I intend to figure out if I am going to keep zenratstudios.org or let it go, and if guardianhero.org is going to be my 'hub'. I have a lot to reflect on. I know that for the sheer amount of projects I am working on, and how non-linear and interconnected my focus is, presenting this project as a digital garden is going to be the way to go. I have to figure out a basic solution that is easy to update, easy to host, and can live on after me - at least for a little while.
</p>
<p>
While I work on that I am going to spend time with my art and my books. I know A.I is going to factor into my projects someway. I have been dreaming of ways to incorporate AI since I was a little kid, and now those things are possible. There's a self-sufficiency project that involves traveling across the eastern USA as a sort of pilgrimage, and other projects like chicken wagons and tractors for poultry and deciding which skills on my bucket list I'm going to pursue or drop. I'm going to post this blog and take a walk - while I continue to explore, what comes next.
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Figuring out what happens now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Refining Vision</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/Refining-Vision.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refining Vision" /><published>2023-02-14T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-14T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/Refining-Vision</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/02/14/Refining-Vision.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/planning_trip-min-960x640.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>Divided between a million different directions. Having a legal and governance structure in place is important. So have, continued to refine the vision for what that looks like and how to ensure our group survives and grows and does not die with one founding family or person. Another challenge is deciding how much or how little we want to share with the world. Will we focus on word of mouth, and leave the website to focus only on the byproduct of what our community produces? Will we share our core binding principals? Are we all in agreement on what those principals are? These questions are big questions to answer, while also working on all the little things forementioned.</p>
<p>
List of elements and focuses:
<ul>
    <li>Organizing our vision and legal structure</li>
    <li>Researching our land options (if any)</li>
    <li>Accessing and developing our current skills.</li>
    <li>Developing Yurt Carpentry skills</li>
    <li>Designing portable off-grid systems designed to scale</li>
    <li>Caring for families, maintaining mental health and wellness</li>
    <li>Narrowing down the viability of the "Medusa Project" as well as the skillsets available to make the project a reality.</li>
    <li>In search for a developmental editor, with potential candidates.</li>
    <li>Building up the studio's physical location and software.</li>
    
</ul>
    
</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Refining Vision]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Niche and Practicality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/18/Narrowing-down.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Niche and Practicality" /><published>2023-01-18T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-18T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2023/01/18/Narrowing-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2023/01/18/Narrowing-down.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/n-map-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>Currently focused on low-risk business concepts that align with our nonprofit goals, which can be used to fund our projects. Assessing our short-term goals and long-term goals, and learning what is feasible and reasonable to expect. Of our long-term goals, village care centers modeled afted Hogeweyk ("Hog vik's") dementia village in the Netherlands has been an important one, to make sure seniors of our monastic family members are well-provided for. Of our short-term goals developing our monastery both an income source and business sense to make these dreams a reality has been the priority. Market analysis and research. We have spent the past few years experimenting with different concepts, and are now returning to the drawing board to see what is possible for us. Developing carpentry skills, purchasing land are part of long-term goals. Creating cashflow is of importance.

</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Narrowing down niche and practicality.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pipeline Improvements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/project-progress.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pipeline Improvements" /><published>2022-11-29T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-29T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/project-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/project-progress.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/fotis-fotopoulos-unsplash.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>Purchased a bunch of tools to help speed up the pipeline. Instead of modeling every scene and detail from scratch we now outsource to asset libraries. Tools were also purchased for managing large Writing Libraries and lore. Web admin roles are now the current focus. Developing and maintaining the website as well as narrowing down the voice and presentation has been a particular challenge. Focusing on practicality over dreams has also been a recent shift.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Progress and pipeline improvements]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Improving Workflow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/Improving-workflow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improving Workflow" /><published>2022-11-29T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-29T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/Improving-workflow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/11/29/Improving-workflow.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/junglegyminterior.jpeg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p>Continued to improve workflow of the site and website administration.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Improving workflow and future updates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual Reality Explorations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/Virtual-Reality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual Reality Explorations" /><published>2022-06-02T02:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T02:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/Virtual-Reality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/Virtual-Reality.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/psv4-VR.png" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>Experimented with the PSVR for possible development of Virtual Environments for VR. The PSVR was a pain to work with PC requiring a lot of hacks. If we go down this route a better investment to purchase the Index Valve from steam. We may wait to see how VR continues to evolve over the years and focus our efforts on 3D Environments.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[PSVR for PS4 to PC]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More Guardian Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/ebike-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More Guardian Updates" /><published>2022-06-02T02:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-02T02:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/ebike-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/06/02/ebike-updates.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/julian-hochgesang-unsplash.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>The goal is to replace local transportation with eBikes. Studied bamboo eBikes and purchased a lightweight used bike with a steel frame from a nonprofit. Current build to add an eBike kit from ebikeling is on hold due to the cost of the kit conflict with the cost of purchasing software for our game and art studio. The eBike build also aligns with our off-grid experimental build, modeled after vandwellers. We currently have one 200w Solar Panel and a 1,500 Generator for recharging a 1,000w Jackery. This is not a fully functioning off-grid solution. The Solar Panels are too heavy, we will need to invest in flexible solar panels. This costs more. More research into diy ebike builds will also need to be explored.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[eBike build progress]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Guardian Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/10/composting-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guardian Updates" /><published>2022-05-10T02:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-10T02:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/05/10/composting-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/05/10/composting-updates.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/chloe-leis-aqVR9n17ejc-unsplash.jpg" alt="Ducks" title="Ducks" /></p>

<p>Around March 10, 2017, we began working on converting all the waste the monastery produces into building and growing materials via vermicomposting. In 2020, it was dubbed a failure, as the red wrigglers required a lot of space and a lot of waste to maintain. In 2019, we switched to Ivory Head Roaches, and in 2020, we added mealworms. This fall of 2022 we added dermestids as well. The dermestids appeared to be dying off after a few months so integrated them with the roach colony. This year we incorporated Mule Ducks (Muscovy x Duck) and chickens into the mix with the goal of producing eggs and using duck fertilizer for growing plants. It turns out poultry is very good at breaking down cardboard. More experimentation is needed.</p>

<p>Current Cage build:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hardware Cloth and accessories,</li>
  <li>Mutt Duckling (Muscovy mixes)</li>
</ul>

<p>Harvesting duck and chicken poop requires some planning. Harvesting clean eggs has been a challenge and finding the best bedding material in a rainy environment has added to the issue. The chickens and ducks free range the garden. In the future we will stick with chickens as opposed to ducks. The ducks are both noisy and messy, but have been a pleasure. Males are up for adoption in pairs and trios. We have ruled out outsourcing to a local butcher known for humane kills, as the sterile ducks have become part of our family. In the future, to make the males worth the cost of feeding them, we would have to accept them as pets (or) harvest their poop and find a use for it. They are very good bug patrol but then so are my egg layers. None of the males are fertile.</p>

<h2 id="guardian-philosophy">Guardian Philosophy</h2>
<p>Guardians have a philosophy called “Kashal” which is a precept Guardians follow but not layman. We can’t eat food whose ingredients we don’t recognize, there can’t be more than 5 whole ingredients in a single product, <em>and</em> any animal we eat has to be an animal we have raised ourselves in compassionate conditions or know beyond doubt have been raised in compassionate conditions. They have to be killed swiftly, without fear or pain, either by hand or by the hands of someone we have witnessed do it. It must be done in a way that does not traumatize the animal or their companions.</p>

<p>We can separate animals into male and female groups, but we cannot separate them from companions in a way which would not have occurred in the wild. Bonded pairs must remain together always except through natural means (such as death). No part of the animal can be wasted, if it rots it has to be used for compost or to feed another animals capable of eating rotten food. We cannot eat bioengineered food that we can’t produce ourselves. And we have to give thanks to the animal for nourishing our bodies. Killing our own food has been harder than expected.</p>

<h2 id="wagon-inspirations">Wagon Inspirations</h2>
<p>The Gustafon family who travel by donkey and wagon and also keeps pigeons and chickens. The family utilizes multiple wagons.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Gustafon_1.webp" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" />
<img src="/assets/img/Gustafon_7.webp" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" />
<img src="/assets/img/Gustafon_6.webp" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" />
<img src="/assets/img/Gustafon_5b.webp" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/Gustafon_JR2.webp" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/gustafon8-DSCN4302c.jpeg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p>In addition Aaron Fletcher who travels with his sheep and guerilla grazes, has also been an inspiration.
<img src="/assets/img/AaronFletcher1.jpg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p>An unknown yurt design - appears lightweight
<img src="/assets/img/yurt-unknown.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>More possible designs
<img src="/assets/img/Playroom.jpeg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/90f6fb7d68a7861cd4f03bfde1e375e5.jpg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p><img src="/assets/img/stout-300x300.jpg" alt="Wagons" title="Wagons" /></p>

<p>Some ideas would be a combination of: Bell tent, yurts with reciprocal roofing, and tipis would be used for portable housing, but for stationary housing round houses made of mycelium bricks, straw, mud, tires, and/or earthbags would be used with reciprocal roofing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian composting Updates]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tool Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/01/tool-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tool Updates" /><published>2022-03-01T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-01T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/01/tool-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/01/tool-updates.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/n-map-unsplash-1024x683.jpg" alt="Trip" title="Trip" /></p>

<p>Attention has been divided between two aspects of the Guardian Project. Getting the Monastery up and running at self-sufficient capacity (and) creating art as a byproduct of that monastery.</p>

<p>Storage and Backup:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Expanded storage with Seagate - 18TB and 14TB</li>
  <li>Repurposed old hard drives from old laptops to expand storage</li>
  <li>Update: 4-Bay Docking Station to remove hard drives from case for easy access.</li>
</ul>

<p>Monastery Tools:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Soldering Station - for repairs and builds</li>
  <li>200w Renogy solar panels w/solar connectors and adapters</li>
  <li>seeds, wheat berries,</li>
  <li>Staple guns and accessories,</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Purchased tools to make Guardian projects easier]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hardware Updates</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/desktop-updates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hardware Updates" /><published>2022-01-01T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-01-01T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/desktop-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/01/desktop-updates.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/assets/img/fotis-fotopoulos-unsplash.jpg" alt="Hardware" title="Hardware" /></p>

<p>Built our own PC to replace old laptop. Invested in a PC build designed to work off-grid in a small space, but also capable of doing the work which needs to be done in the area of 3D Modeling. The old Laptop will remain in use for maintaining the website and basic writing projects.</p>

<p>My current build:</p>
<ul>
  <li>EVGA RTX 3060</li>
  <li>Asus Rog Strix B550-I</li>
  <li>Ryzen 7 5700G</li>
  <li>Corsair Vengeance RGB 32GB (2x16GB)</li>
  <li>Corsair iCue Sp120 RGM 120mm Fan, single pack</li>
  <li>Crucial P2 500GB NvMe PCie M.2 SSD - for “OS only”</li>
  <li>Samsung 980 1TB SSD</li>
  <li>Corsair SF Series, SF750, 750 Watts, 80+ Gold Certified</li>
  <li>Cooler Master NR200 - Mini-ITX case</li>
  <li><em>Monitor is old TCL - Roku TV</em></li>
</ul>

<p>Other tools purchased for the projects: Soldering Station, 18TB Seagate, 14TB Seagate, 200w Renogy solar panels w/solar connectors and adapters, and garden seeds.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Desktop and Hardware Updates]]></summary></entry></feed>